One night a year, all crime is legal.
The Purge is a science fiction, horror, thriller
film directed by James DeMonaco.
Given the country's overcrowded prisons, the U.S.
government begins to allow 12-hour periods of time in
which all illegal activity is legal.
During one of these free-for-alls, a family must
protect themselves from a home invasion.
James Sandin, played by Ethan Hawke.
Mary Sandin, played by Lena Headey.
Charlie Sandin, played by Max Burkholder.
Zoey Sandin, played by Adelaide Kane.
Bloody Stranger, played by Edwin Hodge.
Polite Leader, played by Rhys Wakefield.
The Purge is a 2013 American action horror film
written and directed by James DeMonaco.
It is the first installment in the Purge franchise.
Set in the year 2022, the film stars Ethan Hawke, Lena Headey, Adelaide Kane, and Max Burkholder as members of a wealthy family who find themselves
endangered by a gang of murderers during the annual Purge, a night during which all crime, including murder, is temporarily legal.
The film premiered at the Stanley Film Festival on May 2, 2013, and
released in theaters on June 7, 2013, in the United States.
The Purge was released on DVD and Blu-ray Disc on October 8, 2013.
A 4K UHD Blu-ray release occurred on June 12, 2018.
The film explores themes of california, dystopia,
barricade, bloody fight, home invasion.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.